All right. This, uh, this call is about,
this is a little mini training on how to do product research,
and this is applicable to editors or any script writers or anybody who's
interested. Um, so
basically like, yeah, once I learned this,
it made more sense on how to write scripts much more clearly and, um,
concisely, uh,
versus kind of like throwing everything at the wall and seeing which one is,
you know, what will work. But I'm gonna share the,
the site just really quick. Um,
so this wasn't something, you know, I came up with. This is a,
this is from this guy named Billy bro as, um,
it's called the five light bulb methods or five light bulb framework.
And essentially it, it's broken down into light bulb one,
which is your customer status quo. Um, the way,
what I take from this is like meeting your customer where they're at,
where's that place that they wanna leave, right?
And oftentimes we think of this as like the pain point, right? Um,
it's like if they're in pain, they don't want any pain.
If they don't have any money, they want money. If, you know they're in a pickle,
they wanna be out of the pickle, right?
So that's essentially meeting your customer status quo.
So when you come up with angles in this area,
you just wanna focus on where's that, that the customer wants to leave, right?
The frustrations, um, you know, for example, if it's a pan,
it's like stickiness. Like that's a very common one that we use.
But this is just one segment. And so when you write, when you do research,
you're already thinking, okay, let's, let's list out all of these possibilities,
um, because each one of those could potentially be its own video ad, right?
Or a hook, at least. Moving on to light bulb number two,
other things they've tried, I think this one's a no-brainer,
but comparing all the different choices, right? Um,
making an argument why other alternatives, other competitors,
other products may or may not work for them, right?
This is where us versus them, um, works really well.
Um, and we'll, we'll bring up the pan example. Other things they've tried, okay,
maybe you've tried, you know, getting a nicer pan,
but it's not made with the right stuff. Um,
maybe you've tried air frying or maybe you've tried, you know,
so what are those alternatives, right? Let's list them all down. Um,
third is your approach. And this is where it's all about you and the,
and the product or the service. So this is like what makes it actually unique.
This is like your unique selling proposition that nobody has that makes
your product or service solve their problem. And so if it's a supplement,
it's a special ingredient list, right? If it's the pan,
it's the technology that, you know, the anti stick technology or the high,
high heat, whatever the case may be. If it's the phone, you know,
it's the speed, it's a computer, you know, there's so many of those,
but it's very specific on the features, right? Very specific on like, okay,
I take this, I'm gonna get that result. Um,
the next one is your offer. And this one's kind of like,
if you're not a marketer, it's kind of like, I think harder to kind of imagine,
because you're not like the brand owner, but the offer is just like,
what does it all come with? What does it come with? What's the guarantee?
What does the, uh, the shipping speed? Is it free shipping? Uh, what is it?
Is it come in a nice package? Does it have any freebies?
Does it come with a gift? Does it come with really good customer support?
Does it come with a free trial? Right? These are your offers. So it's like,
what am I gonna get by buying from you today? What am I, like, what's,
what's the difference between buying from somebody else versus buying from you?
And then lastly, you have your customer's new life.
And this is like painting the picture of what life is like after benefiting from
your product. I think this is the one that like most people show off, right?
Um, especially in testimonials. I,
I lost 20 pounds with light bulb magic, you know?
Or I haven't had a,
I haven't had to wash my my pants in a week, right? This is that.
You gotta think ahead. This is the after thought.
So essentially he created this bridge of like, starting from the problem,
their current position, all the way to imagine your life
non-stick, right? So we have to kind of address all of,
so basically how this works is I have to change someone's beliefs
to, in order to get them to buy your product or to even like,
consider buying your product. This is like one thing.
What does my customer need to believe in order to buy?
Because if your prospects have required beliefs, they will buy. If they don't,
they won't buy. This is a priceless insight because it makes your decision,
your mission very clear. Instill the beliefs.
So I think this is really important just because if you're,
if we're not clear on what those are, what all their problems are,
things that they've tried, what makes our product different than anybody else?
What makes our offer different than anybody else?
And what does life look like after using my product or service, right?
So you can literally tell an entire story just by following that entire
framework. But what I like about this is like,
one video doesn't necessarily need to have all of those things.
It could just be focused on, um, things that they've tried,
or just the pain points, and then the customer's new life.
So it's like a mix and match, right? But I, I kind of attribute these to,
to their own Lego blocks, kind of like how we,
we attribute Lego blocks on the, on the editing side, pain points, solution,
animation, social proof, right?
Those are their own mega like bigger categories.
But then you can subcategorize these light bulbs within those, right?
You can have social proof just talking about your offer, social proof,
just talking about customer's new life, right?
So it gets very narrow and specific, but I think it gives a lot of clarity.
Let me find, um, an example. Can
I ask a quick question? Of course. So, um, because I,
I think I understand. Um, but so you just said,
you know,
not every Lego block or whatever has to be inside one piece
of content in the sense that,
because I was going to ask bef prior to you saying that, you know,
when we talk about the different places of the funnel, say mm-hmm.
Um, and ads that serve different purposes. Mm-hmm. So you could literally have,
uh, an ad that, that, you know,
only hits one of those Lego blocks or something, right? It is, it's the,
the strategy as a whole mm-hmm. Is what takes you through that, right?
The the series of videos.
Exactly. Yes. And I think that's a really good question. So,
you know, if you, if you ever heard like a V S L, you know, a 45 minute video,
45 minute was gonna show all of these all aspects aspects, right?
But you know, on Facebook, people have 30 seconds to two minutes.
And so that's where retargeting comes in.
That's where an additional piece of content will come in,
very similar to what you're experiencing right now. Um,
with Rise and all these retargeting people like hitting you up. Yeah.
They're trying to find those pockets, those areas that matter to you, right?
Once they find that one that matters to you, light bulb goes off, oh s**t,
maybe I will try this thing,
You know? Yeah.
They're kind of hitting like light bulbs one and two and just barely touch on
three,
and then kind of like cut it there and then go so that then they can hit me
again like 30,000 times and get to four and five.
Right? But here's the thing, there's like,
you found a weakness in their marketing strategy, right?
Because you have to remember, everybody buys differently.
There's emotional buyers, there's logical buyers,
there's people who impulse buy. There's people who like take their time,
do a lot of research. So you want to be able to cater to all,
and maybe like light bulb number three, their,
your approach is what's missing because they wanna know how it works, right?
They want like authority behind it. They want like a doctor talking about, okay,
well this has actually been studied on and da, da da, and boom,
now you convinced that customer because the other ones they didn't really care
about. So Yeah, no, that's awesome. And you know,
when you present your offer, that's someone who's like maybe added to cart,
who's like just on the fence. It's like, all right, well guys,
you're gonna get all of this. You're right there. Just take the,
just take the bait. Um, but life,
customers do life. Like, these are all like,
just testimonials at the end of the day. That's what I've, I've come to realize
That that's actually one to give credit to the mushroom people rise.
Mm-hmm. Um, they, for one,
they start off all their ads with solid hooks about getting rid of
bloating and losing weight and Right. All of these things.
And then like kind of twisted into like a counterintuitive thing where really
it's about coffee. Mm-hmm. Which you didn't really expect.
So it creates a little bit of surprise. And then they do,
usually they do lean heavily into life with after
the product kind of thing. Yeah. Um,
that's kind of their general vibe mm-hmm. As a whole,
which maybe, you know,
because I am a good target for them in the sense, you know,
like I eat healthy and I exercise and you know,
I do get bloated and I've tried drinking, uh,
lemon water in the morning and things that people have told me. So I mean,
I'm curious and I drink a ton of coffee, so I'm literally drinking it right now.
Yeah. So like it would work, but there is something,
I don't know if it's their price or what,
but I have not bought it and Right.
I have been targeted for a good month and a half now. Yeah. So you,
it's an interesting case study
And that brings up a really good point and that like you're interested but you
haven't had enough evidence to make the buying decision and usually just takes
that one thing, that reassurance, a discount,
somebody you trust who's using it already, you know,
Um, if you were a discount, I'd probably do it if it were like a,
a fat discount. Um,
and I did text Brent one time about it cuz I thought he had been trying some,
so I, like I asked him, um, yeah, but that's the thing is, uh,
it probably doesn't behoove behoove you, uh,
as a marketer to rely on the potential customer reaching out to a
friend to get that validation. Um, you probably wanna provide it instead.
Yeah. So, yeah, so in the shot list, I,
I've incorporated this already into it. Um,
actually not yet the, uh,
the pan video or Hessel hessel Bach, but I will,
um, so the next step in, in doing research, uh,
to find this Hessel Bach,
Haha. Oh,
Yeah's not showing up. Cause I need to be in here.
The next step is actually doing video ad research
and um, is it not created? Oh, there it is. Okay,
Cool. It's, I don't know, it doesn't, if you type the whole name now,
it doesn't show necessarily.
I know. So weird.
So, uh, do you want this, that, uh, to basically,
should we just keep that in our new template of shot lists so that it's just
always there for reference? Yep,
Yep. I like that. Absolutely. Um, so I'll update that,
but um, I'm just, this is, this is a training video,
so I just wanna show the whole process. Yes. Um,
so I'll give you guys access to foreplay if you don't already have it. But, um,
foreplay.co, this is like how I learn everything about ads,
what's working, what's not. Um, log in here.
Let's see. Okay, so I'm already logged in. I'll give you guys a login. Um,
so in discovery,
actually first I'm going to create a new board and call this
Pans. Pans. Just call it Pans. Cause that's what we're looking for, right?
Um, whoops. Let me see. I'll turn on my sound
and I'm gonna move this actually into, uh,
niche specific. Okay. All right. So next I'm gonna go to Discovery.
This is where everyone's ads are saved. Everyone who's on this platform.
So this is actually where I get inspo for ads are X too.
So this is like the dopest. Um,
so what's really cool is that they have AI search right here.
It's all keyword based. So I can type in pans,
but I can also search up brands themselves here.
So under brands, if um, what's the name of the brand that Hex?
Let me try Hex. Okay. Um,
Why, which one?
The hex clad. Is it Clad?
I wanna say like Clad.
So this particular product is said Dutch oven,
So Oh, Dutch Oven Smart. Okay,
So we could search Dutch oven or the fa how high end.
That's the only thing cuz it's cooking. Yes. Boom.
But because there's very high end Dutch ovens,
like the Lake Cruise set and the um,
Yes, I think it's up there. French on, it's up there. Yeah. Cool. Um,
so you know, obviously you're gonna get a ton of stuff. Um,
one of the key things that I look for is I, it's still running.
Um, cuz right now it looks like it was paused,
you know, two years ago. So like this ad maybe not,
is not like relevant anymore, you
Know, so it'll have a green dye if it's running,
Correct. Yeah. Let me find one that's actually still running.
You see this one over here? This one's been running since January 20th,
so that's like actually a good ad. Um,
there's a few companies that I know are absolutely killing it. Um,
let me type in best Dutch oven in Google.
La Cru set.
Staub too. Yeah, I have that one.
So there's an actual brand that, um,
I know. Oh,
check Lo lo l o j oh l o g e.
They're like a, they're the one that make all the cast iron, um,
like pans. But I, I've seen a lot of their advertising,
so I wonder if if they have some quality.
Um, real quick, sorry. So I, yeah, I, I know that one of the brands is,
is our place. This is a very big brand. Um,
so from here I can see that these are still running since June 12th.
Uh, I'm just gonna save it, even if it's an image ad. I'm,
I'm seeing what's out there. Like what's the landscape like, you know, um,
they obviously had like really nice designers. This is an actual video.
I think it's actually a slideshow. Yeah, this is a slideshow. Interesting. Cool.
But, um, you know, the what, what the, what matters here is really the copy,
the do it all countertop connoisseur, like it's a very strong headline.
Um,
but what I can do is go here to this little icon and go to the View brand
and it'll actually show me
all of the ads that have been saved by them. So this actually really cool,
um, looks like, you know, these ones were saved recently, these us versus them.
Okay, let's watch this one. Six,
the six most annoying things about your pots and pans. Boom. That's a good hook,
right?
Mm-hmm.
Hard to use. Toxic chemicals. Heavy, ugly, hard to clean,
no innovative features. All right, this is your offer, right?
Or this is, um, your approach. Light bulb number three,
and then that's it. Um,
I think this is a good concept. I think you could probably expand on that,
right? This one was saved. This is more of like a, uh,
definitely a lifestyle video.
Three reasons why the Upgraded Always Pan is even better than the original.
That's good. It's a good argument. Oh, that's, um, that's, uh,
other things they've tried.
Ready?
First,
We're getting some inspiration of how the videos could potentially look like.
Um, hands cool save ad there. Um,
this is, this is all light bulb number five.
I'm taking Chef Places our placeholder review. That's even better Authority.
Okay, let's watch this one. This is, you can see
I'm obsessed with the Selena Gomez, our place collection.
And the best part is that they just released more colors, more products.
And if you're looking for a steal, the many ones are for you.
This always pan is 10 and one and they're perfect. Pot is eight and one.
Don't even get me started on their incredible toxin, free non-stick.
I used to soak things for hours and now I can run water over my pan for seconds.
What do you get when you combine everyone's favorite star who has her own
cooking show and the makers of iconic cookware?
You get the best collab of all time. Get it before
It's all out. Um, okay, well, so they have Selena Gomez.
That makes a lot of sense.
If there's one product that's made me a better cook, this is it.
So if there's one product that's made me a better cook, this is it.
That's a good, that's a good line. All right.
I got a first look and you're gonna wanna go to our place's site now to see all
the new products they just launched.
The Always Pan is the most multifunctional pan on the market,
replacing 10 pieces of cookware. It's shallow enough to flip an egg,
it's deep enough to roast an entire chicken,
and it goes from stove top right into the oven. The always pan only.
That's cool. That's cool. And you're still running that.
Okay. So there's a ton of inspo here. Um,
but basically from there I would go, you know, as I'm watching these,
I would be going back to the shot list and then writing these headlines down
from some of the hooks, um, potential demos.
And what I mean by assets, I'm like, okay,
what kind of video would be useful here? This A U G C,
this is like talking head us versus them testimonial.
Um, but yeah, I think primarily just getting the, the research down is,
uh, the most important part. And then going from there.
So that concludes our tutorial for today.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna stop recording. Do you have any questions? No,
that makes sense. I.